<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ongoing | Jihua Ouyang</title>
    <link>https://learnerhua.github.io/Home/en/tag/ongoing/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://learnerhua.github.io/Home/en/tag/ongoing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Ongoing</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://learnerhua.github.io/Home/media/icon_hud9f6c1ee21290293ec53f4d5aa012d0a_18286_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Ongoing</title>
      <link>https://learnerhua.github.io/Home/en/tag/ongoing/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comparative Genomic Analysis of the ApeC Protein Family.</title>
      <link>https://learnerhua.github.io/Home/en/project/acps/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://learnerhua.github.io/Home/en/project/acps/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The ApeC domain was originally defined by our team in 2014 within two pattern recognition receptor(&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pattern_recognition_receptor&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;PRRs&lt;/a&gt;) from amphioxus, though these proteins, known as apextrins, were first discovered over twenty years ago. Generally,
we refer to proteins containing the ApeC domain as ACPs. Recent studies have confirmed that ACPs show agglutinating activity but no microbicidal activity to bacteria and participate in controlling the activation of the NF-κB pathway by interacting with TRAF6 moleculer.
Meanwhile, the distribution of ACPs across the taxa has also been elucidated which suggested that they are mainly distributed in invertebrates and can be traced back to early prokaryotes, such as bacteria.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Building upon the previous research, our team is dedicated to clarifying the characteristics and functions of ACPs in various phyla. In our latest research, we further revealed the distribution, structure, and functional characteristics of ACPs in the phylum Mollusca(&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/Taxonomy/Browser/wwwtax.cgi?mode=Info&amp;amp;id=6447&amp;amp;lvl=3&amp;amp;lin=f&amp;amp;keep=1&amp;amp;srchmode=1&amp;amp;unlock&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;taxonomy ID:6647&lt;/a&gt;). I was assigned one of the tasks involving data analysis.
Simultaneously, I am taking charge of the analysing work of ACPs in the phylum platyhelminthes(&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/Taxonomy/Browser/wwwtax.cgi?mode=Info&amp;amp;id=6157&amp;amp;lvl=3&amp;amp;lin=f&amp;amp;keep=1&amp;amp;srchmode=1&amp;amp;unlock&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;taxonomy ID: 6157&lt;/a&gt;), normally known as the flatworm, the species within this phylum are mostly famous for their unparalleled regenerative abilities or notorious parasitic characteristics. Given the fact that intensive aquaculture is severely impacted by parasites, particularly monogenean, our research has been endowed with more practical meaning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Up to now, I have successfully accomplished the majority of tasks in the project and achieved numerous significant research outcomes, including assuring the existence of ACPs in Monogenean and free-living flatworms for the first time, finding that the ApeC domains in flatworms exhibit a repetitive tandem arrangement and so on. I am currently organizing these findings into a publishable academic paper and plan to publish it in the near future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, I have not halted my research efforts and am collaborating with others to explore the functional patterns of ACPs in bacteria.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The impact of the existence or absence of CM on fish’s intestinal microbiota environment</title>
      <link>https://learnerhua.github.io/Home/en/project/microbiomics/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://learnerhua.github.io/Home/en/project/microbiomics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The chitin-based peritrophic matrix (PM) plays a crucial role in gut immunity and digestion in invertebrates. Traditionally, PM was believed to be absent in all vertebrates, however, a recently found PM-like chitinous membrane (CM) in fishes has challenged this notion and has the potential to enhance our understanding of vertebrate gut physiology and structural evolution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this project, our team aimed to investigate if the existence of the CM in  zebrafish gut would have an benefical or harmful impact on the survival of the fish, these two may have no correlation of course. To fullfill our goal, firstly, We created a complete genetic PM/CM knockout model through the prevalent &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/CRISPR&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CRISPR-Cas9&lt;/a&gt; gene editing technology. Then, we designed a series of rigorous experiments to test the influences of the absence of the CM on the fishes, including ingestion
behavior, microbial homeostasis, epithelial renewal, digestion, growth and longevity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a bioinformatics Mphil candidate, I was entrusted with the mission of designing a accurate and stable pipeline to analyse the 16S amplicon sequencing data which was a complexed work obviously. The first challenge we encountered was how to select a suitable platform for conducting our data analysis as there are many microbial data analysis platforms in the field. we ultimately decided to integrate the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.drive5.com/usearch/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;USEARCH&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://qiime2.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;QIIME 2&lt;/a&gt; for our data analysis after careful comparison. Specifically, USEARCH is known for its simplicity and refinement while QIIME 2 is powerful and comprehensive, they complement each other excellently. In fact, we solely utilized USEARCH to generate the feature table, which was the central step in the entire process and subsequent analyses were primarily conducted using relevant plugins from QIIME 2.
In order to enhance the reproducibility of the data analysis and facilitate potential interested researchers, I developed a simple software called &amp;ldquo;LuckyMicrobe.&amp;rdquo; Detailed information about this software can be found on my GitHub page(&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Learnerhua/LuckyMicrobe-testing-&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://github.com/Learnerhua/LuckyMicrobe-testing-&lt;/a&gt; ), though it is still in the experimental stage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently, this research topic is still being further extended, and our team has a continuous demand for data analysis. As a result, this project remains ongoing, and I continue to improve my software constantly.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A concise R language tutorial</title>
      <link>https://learnerhua.github.io/Home/en/project/external-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://learnerhua.github.io/Home/en/project/external-project/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
